你好
hello
我的名字是Logimer
my name is logimer
我是一名前端开发
I'm a front
我是一名前端开发员，目前我在一个峰会上工作。
end developer and currently I'm working for a summit
zamat是一个开源的服务台票务软件
zamat is an open source help desk ticketing software
我们对我们的开源理念感到自豪
we are proud of our open source philosophy
所以每个人都可以在自己的服务器上运行zama
so everyone can run zama on their own servers
为此，我们有一个不断增长的社区
and to that we have a constantly growing community
我也是1
I am also 1/4 team member in v test
null
test ranul that we also use in zamat
and today I'm going to talk about
null
how wheatest improves your developer experience
wheatest
null
was originally developed as an alternative to just
for wheat applications
null
because just didn't didn't
have support for synchrons transforms
null
and many of wheat's API
let's build a top of wheat note package
null
which is an ogs run time that use a sweet
to transform files before running it
null
but right now the test is
fully flash test runner
null
like I adjust our top mocha or any other test runner
tries to be feature each
null
without unnecessary configuration
it provides esm
null
typescript and gsx support out of the box
thanks to vid pure
null
some of the widest features
wid test uses vit configuration file
null
including transformers resolvers and plugins
so you have the same cod in development production and
null
in testing vitas has smart an instant watch mode
in fact it's so so fast
null
that we had to add
an artificial delay before displaying result
null
in a terminal
it uses sweets module graph to detect imports
null
which makes experience similar
to each Mar in your browser
null
you can run v test
to test your components using your favorite framework
null
like a view react spelt
many more
null
if your framework supports VT it supports v test
vitas comes with the Chi built in for assertions
null
it means you can use its assert
should or expect apivs with v test
null
but for these immigration we also provide
just expect compatible API
null
like to be too equal to much and so on
smoke domain piv test provides GS
null
dom and happy dome
内置的环境，你也可以扩展
built in environments that you can also extend
为caverage v test提供了一个报告。
for caverage v test provides a reporting with
和伊斯坦布尔的开箱即用的报告
ch and Istanbul out of the box
此外，v测试还具有独特的前台和
also v test has a unique among front and
测试运行器的功能
test runners feature
叫做insores测试
called insores testing
它的灵感来自于Rust的模块测试
which was inspired by rust's module testing
我们还提供了实验性的基准和功能
and we also provide experimental benchmark and feature
的功能。
via a
小板凳包
tiny bench package
所以现在
so now
当你知道什么是机智主义的时候，让我们来看看它的实际应用吧
when you know what witist is let's see it in action
这里我们有一个视图3组件
here we have a view 3 component
使用scrape设置语法
using scrape setup syntax
你可以在这里看到
as you can see here
用一个简单的测试来租借它并检查一些
with a simple test that renters it and checks some
输出，我们可以在快照中看到这个组件
output this component as we can see in a snapshot
有一个div和一个按钮，可以增加它的乘数
has a div and a button that increases its multiplier
这个快照是由vidis生成的
this snapshot is generated by vidis
正如你在这里看到的第一行
as you can see here in the first line
快照功能等同于喷气式快照
the snapshot feature is equal to jet snapshot
所以，如果你是从刚开始的时候迁移过来的，你应该不会有问题。
so if you are migrating from just you should be fine
所以让我们来运行这个
so let's run this
我在运行它时使用了
I'm running it with
UI标志，所以你可以看到如果你的
UI flag so as you can see if your
测试是否提供了漂亮的UI
test provides your beautiful UI
来查看和互动
to view and interact
与你的测试互动
with your tests
正如你所看到的，它并没有
and as you can see it doesn't
显示你的渲染组件
show you rendered component
我们在这里可以看到
which we can see here
因为这个用户界面不是用来做这个的，但是我们有
because this UI is not meant for this but we have
一个叫做vitas浏览器的包
a package called vitas browser
的软件包，可以查看它
that enables viewing it
但它还处于实验阶段，而且
but it's in an experimental stage and
我没有设法让它在这里工作
I didn't manage to make it work for this
遗憾的是
damn unfortunately
但当你看到这个的时候，它可能会
but by the time you're watching this it will probably
工作
work
这个
this
你我为你提供这种方式
you I provide you with that way
来
to
看到一个报告，所以如果这个是
see a report so if this is
如果这有一个错误，你会在这里看到一个错误。
if this had an error you would see an error here
这个用户界面还允许你过滤你的测试
this UI also allows you to filter your tests
以
to
只运行
run only
过滤测试，以过滤
filter tests to filter
本地测试
local tests
你也可以穿上像这样的测试只有一个这样的
you can also wear like this test only has one so
和哪个
and which
我最喜欢的一个功能是模块图
a feature that I like the most is module graph
你可以在这里看到这是一个相当简单的测试
you can see here this is a quite a simple test
所以模块图是相当小的
so module graph is quite small
但对于更大的应用程序来说，它非常有用，可以看到
but for bigger applications it's very useful to see
你的所有文件是如何
how all your files are
彼此之间的关系
introducting with each other
但最好的功能之一
but one of the best features
是你可以
here is that you can
在浏览器中直接编辑你的测试
edit your tests right in the browser
我保存这个，我可以看到发生了一个断言错误
I save this and I can see an assertion error happened
而且我可以看到它发生在哪里
and I can see where it happened
而且我还可以在报告中看到它
and I can also see it in a report
我可以点击打开一个编辑器，它将为我打开这个
I can click open an editor and it will open this
步骤，所以我们可以在这里看到它期望当我们
step for me so as we can see here it expects when we
是
are
在尖端线3乘以2期望6，但这里我们有一个4
on tipline 3 by 2 expect 6 but here we have a 4
乘以2更好，所以让我们
multiply better by 2 so let's
暂时将其恢复为4
revert this to 4 for now
现在我们的测试运行良好
now our test runs fine
因为这个测试是为了解决胸部问题而做的
since the test was made to fix chest issues
我们只提供兼容的API，以便更容易迁移
we provide just compatible API for easier migration
正如你所看到的，我们在这里使用了2个包含
as you can see here we are using 2 contain
和太多的快照匹配器
and too much snapshot matchers
完全与just兼容。
which are fully compatible with just
但我们不仅支持预期的API，还支持
but not only do we support expect API will also support
just API
只是全局变量，如果你曾经写过类似于
just global variable if you've ever written caught like
这个
this
我是说这个小破坏者
I mean this this little spoiler
你可以用同样的方法在
you can use the same in
v test
但我们没有默认，我们没有暴露变量
but we don't by default we do not expose just variable
但我们有自己的
but we have our own
变量，具有相同的API
variable with the same API
公共API，它被称为v或test
public API it's called v or test
你可以使用你最喜欢的那一个，我们通常
you can use which one you prefer the most we usually
建议使用v
recommend using v
所以如果你有
so if you have
如果你想看看你的测试是如何
if you want to see how your tests are
在v测试下的运行情况
running under v test
下运行的情况，但你又不想让你的测试从刚开始就很好。
but you don't want to make great from just
就马上进行
just right away
你可以使用这个小技巧
you can use this little trick
你可以给v指定一个全局的，非常有能力的
you can assign a global this just very able to v
而你的所有
and all your
方法都能正常工作
methods should work fine
如果我们仍然有一些分歧
if we just still have some differences
我们在我们的狗中提供了迁移指南，记录了所有的
we provide migration guide in our dogs documenting all
这些差异
these differences
但在大多数情况下，它应该工作
but for the most part it should work
我们还提供给你，你可以看到这里只是一个风扇
and we also provide you as you can see here just a fan
是一个间谍，所以
is a spy so
维塔斯也
vitas also
有香料，这些香料与
has spice which are fully compatible with
justspice有相同的方法和名称
justspice with the same methods and the names
等等，等等。
and so on and so forth
但V测试的最佳功能可能是它的
but probably the best feature of a v test is its
观察模式
watch mode
让我们删除这个
let's remove this
它只运行
it runs only
有效的测试
the effective tests
因此，例如这里
so for example here
正如你所看到的，它向我展示了重新排列的
as you can see it showed me rearrange for
当我把这个测试弄老时，它将只重新运行这个测试，但
when I aged this test it will rerun only this test but
这并不是它的终点
this is not where it ends
如果我们正在编辑这个组件
if we are editing this component
这个组件，例如，我们可以添加一个新的按钮
this component here for example we can add a new button
增加2的乘数
that adds multiplier by 2
递增2
incremented by 2
现在我们可以看到
now we can see that
我们的任务已经失败了，因为停止拍摄
our task has failed because stop shot
不等于它所产生的快照
that we have is not equal to the snapshot
它现在生成的快照
that it generates now
所以我们现在可以
so let's for now we can
把它注释掉
comment it out
让我们现在来测试一下我们的新按钮
let's let's now test our new button
这里我将添加
here I will add
和你
and you
像这样测试
test like this
我不认为这是
I don't think this is
是最好的方法
the best way to do it
我可能会
I would probably
通过里面的文字得到它
get it by the text inside
但现在我认为这很好
but for now I think it's fine
我们正在触发它
we're triggering it
我们现在触发它，我们期望
we trigger it now and we expect
我认为
I think
4应该被增加2，我们现在有
4 should be incremented by 2 and we now have
6个6，也就是24
6 6 which is 24
我们保存这个测试，它运行良好
we save this this test and it runs fine
顺便说一下，你可以看到
by the way as you can see
测试的实际时间是132,000,000秒
the actual duration of test is 132,000,000 seconds
这是相当快的
which is quite fast
我们认为这种体验是比较好的
we think that this experience is preferable
所以我们默认启用观察模式
so we enable watch mode by default
如果你没有用
if you don't override it with
品牌标志
brand flag
所以我想这是前端部分的全部内容
so I think this is all for front end part
但
but
你不一定要在前端框架中使用v测试
you don't have to use v test with front end frameworks
事实上，我的v test不仅仅是
in fact I v test is not just
一个默认的测试运行器
a test runner by default
所以你可以在这里看到这是一个简单的
so as you can see here this is a simple
无js应用
nojs application
只是一个平方根函数
just a square root function
我们正在测试这里的值是否正确
we are testing here that the values are correct
你可以看到这是配置文件
this as you can see is the configuration file
没有任何配置
nothing is configured
所以这是由defold完成的
so this is by defold
现在我们来运行这个
now let's run this
你可以看到一切都通过了
and as you can see everything is passing
该测试有一个上下文的概念
the test has a concept of contexts
的概念，其灵感来自于playwright的固定装置
which was inspired by fixtures from playwright
上下文是
context are
一个对象
an object
以1的形式传递
that is passed as 1/1 argument
null
to your test so here we can see that
this has a type of test context
null
by default it has
meta and expect
null
so you can have local expects
this is a useful for concurrent testing
null
if you have for example if you
are doing too much snapshot inside a concurrent test
null
but you can put things here
for example we can use before each
null
function to put something on the context
expect
null
context
or
null
sorry context
4 to be one not really
访问，开始传递
accessed that start passing
但类型蠕变向我们显示了一个错误
but the types creep shows us an error
为了绕过这个错误，我们需要定义一个接口
to bypass this error we need to define an interface
是一个数字
who is a number
我们可以将这个接口作为
we can pass down this interface as
一个通用的
a generic
所以我们需要把它传下去
so we will need to pass it down
为每一个我们需要的测试的上下文
for each test that we need the context
我们还可以
we can also
定义
define
全局定义，例如我们可以这样做
it globally for example we can do
声明模块e测试
declare module e test
接口文本上下文 谢谢你
interface text context thank you
所以现在它知道每个测试都有这个上下文
so now it knows that every test has this context
你的整个套件中的每个测试都会有这个上下文
every test in your entire suite will have this context
有一个更简单的方法
there is a simpler way
使用标签脚本
with using tab script
比如说
for example
你可以做一个完整的测试，就是带有上下文的测试
you can do a full test is test with context
现在我们可以删除这个
now we can remove this
也许应该在这里做
probably should do it here
但现在
but now
我们可以做食品测试，它将有这个上下文
we can do food test and it will have this context
它就会知道这个测试的上下文
it will know the context of
这个测试
this test
注意，这是不相容的，不相容的。
about beware that thisthis is incompatible incompatible
不相容的只是
incompatible is just
我们只是在这里做了一个colbeck。
we're just had a done colbeck here
所以如果你在这里调用这个
so if you are calling this here
你可以看到它已经被废弃了。
as you can see it's deprecated
如果你在这里调用它
if you are calling it here
你会得到
you will get
一个错误 上下文不是
an error context is not
我很抱歉，但你所发现的是
I'm sorry but just what you find is
这里
here
现在设置这个
set this now
如果你在这里调用完成
if you are calling done here
它就会告诉你，它已经被废弃了
it will call you that it is deprecated
而你应该用一个承诺来代替
and you should use a promise instead
所以为了模拟一个
so to emulate a
的回调，你可以像这样返回承诺
done callback from just you can return the promise
就像这样，测试将通过
like this and the test will pass
每个
each
测试都有自己的上下文，所以
test has its own context so
比如说
for example
你不能在所有回调之前访问上下文
you cannot access context in before all callback
没有上下文
doesn't have a context
但它有
but it does by the way
有一个访问当前甜味的
have an access to sweet current sweet
或文件，无论它是什么
or file whichever it is
比如说，他们会访问它的名字
they're gonna access its name for example
我想它有一个
I think it has a
文件路径 是的
file path yeah
我想这就是我想谈的全部内容了
I think this is all I wanted to talk about
与
with
语境
contexts
vitas还有一个很酷的功能
there is also one cool feature that vitas has
它叫做vitas改变
it's called vitas changed
所以你可以在这里看到
so as you can see here
我们
we
编辑了一个文件
edited one file
我们改变了一个文件
we changed one file
一个测试，而且我们不想把整个种子圆起来。
a test and we don't want to round the whole seeds
整个套件的测试
whole suite tests
所以我们可以做的就是运行测试变更
so we can do what we can do is run test change
这就是测试变更的命令
and this is the test change command
它将
and it will
查看所有被修改的文件，并只运行
see all the files that are changed and run only
重要的测试
tests that are important
或重要的测试，或测试本身。
or important by it or thator the test itself
例如，在这里我们编辑了一个测试
for example here we edited the test
我们看到测试被改变了
and we see the test changed
如果我们回滚，我们应该看到没有什么
if we rolled back we should see nothing
变化，没有测试会运行
changed and no tests will run
但最酷的功能是
but the cool feature is is
如果我们在这里添加一个理事会锁，例如
what if we added here for example a council lock
命名为字符串
pername to string
我们现在可以运行
we can now run
测试改变，它将运行一个基本测试，因为
test changed and it will run a basic test because
这个功能很重要
this function is important
这里
here
它是物理的
which is physical
现在让我们来谈谈源码测试
now let's talk about in source testing
这个功能允许你把测试写在
this feature allows you to write
你的测试在你的源代码中
your tests inside your source code
你为什么要这样做
why would you do that
这个功能很有用
well this feature could be useful
对很多事情都有用
for a number of things
例如，用于单元测试
for example for unit testing
小范围的函数或实用程序
small scope functions or utilities
就像幻灯片上的内容
like here on the slide
例如，如果你有一个文件集，其中有一个
for example if you have a collection of files with a
单一函数诶
single function eh
你可以把你的测试放在这个文件里
you can keep your tests inside that file
它对原型设计也很有用
it's also useful for prototyping
如果你在编写程序的同时编写测试，你可以
if you are writing tests alongside your program you
可能
might
更加专注于
be more focused on the
功能本身
functionality itself
你也可以在程序中进行内联断言
you can also make inline assertions
就在你的程序中
right inside your program
例如
for example
你可以在你的函数中测试一个中间值
you can test an intermediate value in your function
在一个私有方法的内部做一个断言也是很有用的。
it's also useful to make an assertion inside
做出断言也很有用，例如
of a private method for example
你不能导出或在构造函数内部
that you cannot export or inside a constructor
这也很有用
it's also useful
测试函数
to test function
也很有用，可以测试你想保留在特定模块内的函数
that you want to keep inside a specific module
而不导出它
without exporting it
例如，如果add函数有某种帮助器
for example if add function had some kind of a helper
它被定义在这里
it was defined here
你可以测试这个辅助器
you could have tested this helper
在这个模型中被孤立地测试
in isolation right inside this model
而不公开导出它
without exporting it publicly
这可能是这里最有用的情况
which might be the most useful case here
但我们确实建议你
but we do recommend you
对更复杂的测试使用单独的测试文件，如
to use separate test files for more complex tests like
组件
components
输入和测试
enter and testing
因为它们通常需要更复杂的设置
because they usually require more complex setup
如使用库交出
like using libraries surrender
设置组件
set components
例如这里
for example here
这段代码将被从你的生产代码中剥离出来
this code will be stripped out from
你的生产代码中剥离出来，因为它是
your production code because it's
被导入所保护
guarded by import
将会是无限制的或虚假的metavitist
metavitist which will be unsufined or false
无论你想要什么
whichever you want
但如果你使用的是某种进口的
but if you are using some kind of an import
屏幕，例如从
screen for example from
测试库
the testing library
testing library
穹顶
dome
其他单一的圆顶有这个反应
other single dome has this react
这可能
this might
是
be
与你的生产代码捆绑在一起
bundled with your production code
即使你只在这里使用它
even if you use it only here
因为我认为你需要
because I think you need
一个副作用
a side effect
副作用
side effect
适当地在你的软件包和
appropriately in your packages and
在模块本身的打包过程中
in the packageation of the module itself
来说明它可以被安全地删除
to specify that it can be safely removed
我认为这些都是
I think this is all
的内容
for
我有时间向你展示的功能
features that I had time to show you
让我们来讨论一下v测试的下一步是什么
and let's talk about what is coming next for v test
因为
since
v test
在书中提供了类型脚本的支持
provides type script support out of the books
我们认为这将是一个好主意
we thought it would be a good idea to
我们认为应该为类型测试提供支持
make senseto also provide support for type testing
各种各样的开箱即用
all sorts of out of the box
所以我们有一个操作性很强的C，你可以留下评论。
so we have an operative c which you can leave a comment
目前，我们正在考虑
currently we are thinking about
为类型测试提供2个apis，就像你为普通的常规测试所做的那样。
providing 2 apis for type tasting like you do for
常规的常规测试 对不起
regular regular tasting sorry
这就是期望和断言
which is expect and assert
所以会有一个期望类型的
so there will be an expect type of
函数
function
暴露了类似于expect
which exposes similar to expect
匹配器喜欢匹配相等的类型和
matchers like to match the equal type and
等等，并且
so on and
它的灵感来自于期望类型包
it is inspired by expect type package
而我们也认为
and we also think
我们还认为，我们将
that we will
有一个断言类型的函数，它是
have an assert type function which was
它的灵感来自于tsd
which is inspired by tsd
但请继续关注这个问题
but stay tuned for that
它还没有实现，只是一个
it's not implemented yet it's only an
C互联网的阶段
internet of c stage
但已经实现的是基准测试
but what is implemented is benchmarking
它已经实现了，但我们在想
it's already implemented but we are thinking
我们可以做得更好
that we can do better
比如说
for example
目前我们对输出的结果不满意
currently we are not happy with the result output
我们在想
we are thinking
API可以改进
that API could be improved
并在此功能之前实现标准化
and standardized before this feature
失去其实验性标志
loses its experimental flag
最好的办法就是我之前说的
the best also is I said before
提供一个Vita的浏览器包
provides a vita's browser package
用于在浏览器中预览你的测试
for previewing your tests in browser
但目前它不支持在CI中尝试测试
but currently it doesn't support trying tests in ci
但它可以对失败的测试进行处理。
but it can be useful to jibach your failing tests
这个功能还没有准备好用于生产
this feature is not ready for production use
在这个阶段，它甚至可能对你不起作用。
and it might even not work for you at this stage
但我们始终欢迎反馈意见，抱歉
but we're always welcome feedback feedback sorry
所以请随时在
so feel free to open an issue in
关于此功能的问题
about this feature
现在，我们还想改进评论。
right now we also want to improve the commentation
目前评论的状态是，它是在
the current state of the commentation is that it was
写在
written before the
hts离开实验阶段之前写的
hts left experimental stage
而且它更多的关注于迁移和仅仅是API
and it focuses more on migration and just API
并没有帮助新人们
and doesn't help a new people
习惯于胎儿本身
get accustomed to fetus itself
所以这就是我想和你谈的全部内容
so this is all I wanted to talk to you about
谢谢你听我的演讲
thank you for listening to my talk